演講 演講
Speech! Speech!
好啦好啦 都靜一下
Okay, okay, okay. Settle down.
真不敢相信我50歲了
It's hard to believe I'm 50.
從今天開始 我就步入中年了
A-A-As of today, I'm middle-aged.
那他過去十年算什么
What's he been the last 10 years?
妄想狂 他以為自己跟我們一樣是千禧一代
Delusional. He thinks he's a millennial, like us.
我思考了很多 關于接下來會如何
I've thought a lot about what's next.
-變51歲 -謝謝你啊 兄弟
- 51. - Thank you, buddy.
重要的是 我要繼續成長
And it's important that I continue to grow
并且繼續接受精神上的挑戰[當弱智]
and that I stay mentally challenged.
所以我要開始
Which is why I am starting...
學鋼琴
piano lessons,
這樣到明年生日時
so that by next year's birthday,
我就厲害到能當眾演奏了
I'll be good enough to perform in public.
太好了 又有破事要去參加
Oh, great. Another thing to go to.
還有 我要學講西班牙語
Also, I'm gonna learn how to speak Spanish.
好棒哦[西語]
Excelente!
我還沒開始學 聽不懂
Uh, I -- I haven't started yet.
最終
Um, and finally, um --
我知道這算是老掉牙的中年危機事項
and I know it's a little bit of a midlife-crisis cliché,
不過
but...
我打算學騎獨輪車
I'm gonna learn how to ride a unicycle!
菲爾 有份禮物你忘記拆了
Phil, you forgot to open one of your gifts.
這一份 是杰親手為你選的
This one, Jay picked it up for you himself.
真的嗎
He did?
爸爸
Hey, Dad.
你干嘛戴那頂帽子
So, what's going on with that hat?
歌洛莉亞覺得我在我們家庭聚會拍的大合照里
Gloria thinks I look grumpy in the photos that we take
都很臭臉
when we go to these things,
所以我在尋找最合適的帽子
so I'm searching for the right hat
能讓我看起來玩得很開心
that makes me look like I'm having fun.
或者你多笑一點也行啊
Or you could just smile more.
《品酒師的法國紅酒指南》
"The Sommelier's Guide to the Wines of France."
-我太喜歡了 -真不錯
- I love it so much. - Nice!
老天爺 上面還題了字
Oh, my goodness. It's inscribed.
"愿你像上等波爾多紅酒般
"May you continue to age
繼續優雅地老去"
as gracefully as a fine Bordeaux."
-爸爸 -"生日快樂 杰
- Dad... - "Happy Birthday, Jay.
愛你的 小卡"
Love, Cam."
小卡 沒錯 杰 你把我送你的禮物轉送人啊
...Cam. Yeah. Jay, you re-gifted my gift?
爸爸
Dad!
我不知道他在里面寫字了
I didn't know he wrote in it.
因為你都沒打開過
Because you didn't open it.
現在我覺得自己好混蛋
So now I feel like a jerk.
你怎么會是混蛋呢 你可是戴著那頂可愛的小帽子
How could you be a jerk? You're wearing that hat.
一年后 我就知道她在說什么了
A year from now, I'm gonna know what that means.
我給歌洛莉亞準備了最棒的情人節禮物
I got Gloria the greatest Valentine's Day gift --
喜劇演員迪恩·馬丁的全套吐槽作品集
a box set of DVDs of all the Dean Martin Roasts.
我被如此浪漫的舉動深深打動了
I was so moved by the romantic gesture
于是杰生日那天
that for Jay's birthday,
我邀請了一群人來羞辱他
I invited a bunch of people over to insult him.
我前妻和我
So, my ex-wife and I,
我們跟杰和歌洛莉亞一起去度假
we were on vacation with Jay and Gloria.
他倆沿著海灘漫步 我前妻說
They're walking down the beach, and my ex-wife says,
"天啊 露出那么大面積的皮膚"
"Whoa, look at all that skin."
我便說 "寶貝 別這樣
And I said, "Baby, come on.
那有什么問題呢
What's wrong with that?
她是個穿著比基尼的美麗女子"
She's a beautiful woman in a bikini."
她說 "不 我是在說杰的頭皮"
She said, "Oh, I'm talkin' about Jay's scalp."
杰毫無拉丁血統
Jay is so not Latin
沒有的程度達到他只要開始跳舞
that every time that he dances,
都有人告訴他洗手間在哪
people point him to the bathroom.
他毫無節奏感 我意思是
He has no rhythm. That's what I mean.
不過說真的 我很喜歡白人
But seriously, I love the whites.
不 說真的 杰是不折不扣的環保人士
No, but seriously, Jay is quite the environmentalist.
去年 他就把我送他的禮物回收利用了
Just this last year, he recycled a gift of mine --
是一本關于上等紅酒的好書
a wonderful book about wine.
我不想說我爸年紀很大
I-I don't want to say my father is old,
不過他對1000年電腦千年蟲的恐懼還記憶猶新
but he remembers panicking at Y-1-K.
我爸很老了
My dad is old.
他有多老
How old is he?
他一開始用白宮H牌痔瘡膏那個年代
He's so old that when he started using it,
那還叫白宮家御用古方痔瘡膏
it was called Preparation G.
夠了
Enough!
你們太過分了
This is terrible!
我不懂你們為什么覺得好笑
I don't know why any of you people think this is funny!
你們可能覺得這些只是玩笑 但其實太真實了
You may think these are jokes, but it's way too real.
我們應該尊敬外公 而不是揭他老底
We need to respect Grandpa instead of cutting him down.
沒人知道他還能活多久
None of us really knows how much time he has left.
你們真的希望這是他人生最后聽到的話嗎
Do you really want these to be the last words he hears?
現在我難受死了
Well, now I feel like hell.
這才叫吐槽 炸裂
And that's how you roast! Bam!
我不懂大人為什么把生日
I don't understand why adults make such a big deal
搞得那么隆重
about their birthdays.
所以今年 我沒有任何要求
So this year, I asked for nothing.
不搞派對 不搞活動
No party, no fuss.
一個人靜靜度過那晚
Just a quiet night by myself,
與我的思想獨處
with my thoughts, all alone.
好了
Okay.
跟我希望的一樣 米奇爾凄慘到不行
Just as I had hoped, Mitchell is miserable.
他說他不想辦派對
He said he didn't want a party,
但這就跟你在邀請函上寫"不用送禮"
but it's like when you write "No gifts" on an invitation
其實暗中希望所有人都帶大份
but you secretly want everyone to bring something
又昂貴的禮物來一樣 約坦
big and expensive, Jotham.
我在你的派對上發表了真誠的祝酒辭
I made a heartfelt toast at your party.
沒錯 那12個詞跟其他人帶來的實體禮物
Yes, and those 12 words were just as generous
同樣慷慨大方
as the actual physical gifts everyone else brought.
好 我要進去了
Okay, I'm gonna go in.
你們聽到我說"米奇爾 你不是一個人"后
When you hear me say "Mitchell, you're not alone,"
你們就沖進來大喊"驚不驚喜"
that's when you come in and you yell "Surprise."
我們知道該說什么
We know what to say.
你真的知道嗎
Mm. Do you?
-你怎么樣 還好嗎 -嗯
- How you doing? Okay? - Yeah.
現在你知道獨自過生日是什么樣了吧
Now do you see what it's like to spend your birthday alone?
知道了 這...
I do. And it's...
-對 -簡直太棒了
- Yeah. - ...amazing.
-什么 -小卡 謝謝你 謝謝你
- What? - Cam, thank you. Thank you.
你終于有一次聽進去我的話 給我我想要的
For once, you heard me and gave me exactly what I wanted
而不是你以為我該想要的
instead of what you thought I should want.
親愛的 這是我收到過最棒的生日禮物
Honey, this is the best birthday present ever.
-真的嗎 -真的
- It is? - Yes!
你一定也松了一口氣吧
Oh, and you've -- you've got to be relieved, too.
我們每次跟那群朋友玩
I mean, every time we hang out with our friends,
他們走后 你都花一整晚
they leave and you spend the rest of the night
抱怨他們每一個人都哪里惹到你了
complaining about how every single one of them annoys you.
我不知道你在說什么
I don't know what you're talking about!
少來 約坦很小氣 勒邁克有口臭
Oh, please. Jotham's cheap. L'Michael has bad breath.
我才不會說這種話
That doesn't sound like me!
安東尼奧的編發都快散架了
Antonio's weave is falling apart.
文森特喝醉后都失控
Vincent's a sloppy drunk.
還有 杰弗里每次都把女星
Oh, oh, Jeffrey won't stop telling
伯納黛特·彼特斯的同個故事拿出來講
his one Bernadette Peters story.
你喝醉后才失控呢
You're the sloppy drunk!
驚不驚喜
Surprise!
我發現了一件事
Here's a thing I realized --
只要不過生日 就永遠不會老
you can't get older if you never have birthdays.
? 祝你生日... ?
♪ Happy birth-- ♪
我說什么來著
What'd I tell you?
我以為今年她終于會坦然接受
I thought this would be the year.
我之前跟家人說 今年生日
I told my family I just wanted my birthday
我只想跟迪蘭兩個人過 因為當時
to be me and Dylan this year because at the time,
我還沒告訴家人我懷孕了
I was still keeping my pregnancy a secret,
我知道他們見到我不喝酒
and I knew they'd get all suspicious
肯定會開始懷疑
about why I wasn't drinking.
我能怎么說
What was I going to say?
"我要早起工作所以不能喝酒"嗎
"I can't drink because I have work in the morning"?
他們才不可能相信
There's no way they'd believe that.
給 我給你準備了禮物
Here. I got you a present.
謝謝你
Thank you!
不是吧
Get out!
古琦嬰兒鞋
Gucci baby sneakers!
真可愛
They're adorable.
我們的寶寶會很性感的
Our baby's gonna be so hot.
就我個人來說 我覺得這很怪
Personally, I think it's weird
寶寶還不會走路為什么要穿鞋
that there are shoes for someone who can't walk.
但你知道嗎 海莉
But you know what, Haley?
我們懷了寶寶我真高興
I love that we're pregnannnt --
你們好
Hello!
你們倆怎么會在這
What are you guys doing here?
在這間餐廳嗎 我們
At the restaurant? We got a --
-我們買了團購券 -我們也是
- We got a Groupon, but we -- - Us too.
我們只是看到你們倆在這邊
Yeah, we j-we just saw that you were over here.
-想過來說聲生日快樂 -生日快樂
- Wanted to say happy birthday. - Happy birthday.
我們無意偷聽
Didn't mean to overhear.
你們什么都沒聽到
You didn't overhear anything.
我們剛才說的是電視劇
We were talking about a TV show.
那這些
Oh, well, then, what's-what's up
這些嬰兒鞋是怎么回事
with these little baby shoes, then?
這些不是嬰兒鞋
These are-these are not baby shoes.
不是 這些是
No, they're, um...
我們要創業
We are starting a business
賣這些給買不起正常尺寸奢侈品的人
for people who cannot afford full-size designer wear.
盡管聽起來像是你會做的事 我
Oh. Well, as much as that does sound like you, I --
好吧
Okay.
-我懷孕了 -我的天
- I'm pregnant. - Oh, my God.
太令人激動了
That's exciting!
-是嗎 -我們覺得是
- Is it? - We think so.
但我們還沒告訴我父母
But we have not told my parents yet,
所以拜托什么都別說
so please don't say anything.
親愛的 我可以永遠為你保守秘密
Oh, honey, I could keep your secret forever,
但你得知道 他做不到
but just so you know, he can't.
是的 我嘴不嚴
Yeah, I'm weak.
他最多只能忍住三四天
Yeah, you got maybe three, four days tops.
-什么 -是的
- What? - Yeah.
好吧 這些本來是我們送的 可是
Okay. Well, these were from us, but...
她不能喝酒 她懷孕了
Yeah, she can't have it. She's pregnant.
這就說了 你瞧
Okay, there you go. See?
你給我聽好
Now, you listen to me.
我過山車一樣的荷爾蒙
My roller-coastering hormones
現在不能應付我媽再對我說教
cannot handle another lecture from my mother right now,
所以你得告訴我一個秘密
so you are going to tell me a secret
假如你泄密 我就告訴所有人
that I will reveal to everyone if you ever spill mine!
可我沒有任何秘密
Yeah, but I don't have any secrets.
他扮成費茲波的時候
Uh, when he dresses as Fizbo,
全身每一處地方都要化妝
he puts the makeup everywhere.
你最好了
You're the best.
因為21歲生日是件大事
Because of the whole 21 thing,
人們不覺得20歲生日有多重要
people don't think turning 20 is a big deal.
但過去三年里我腦子里只想著這件事
But it's all I've been thinking about for the last three years.
三年前 我到這家店來
Three years ago, I came in here,
一看到你就愛上了你
and when I saw you, I fell in love.
是那種對人沖擊很大
The kind of love that punches you in the gut
讓我想變得更優秀的愛情
and makes you wanna be a better man.
但我約你出去時 你說
But when I asked you out, you said,
"抱歉 孩子 你很可愛
"Sorry, kid. You're cute,
但我不跟青少年約會"
but I don't date teenagers."
你看
Well... check it out.
生日快樂
Happy birthday!
可現在我不跟"男人"約會了
But now I don't date men.
看來我有個重大決定要做
Well...looks like I've got a decision to make.
我今年過生日時
On my birthday this year,
真的明白了人們是怎么看我的
I really got a sense of what people think of me.
那真是
Which is...
好啊
so great.
這是我和小伙子們合送的
This is from me and the boys.
歌洛莉亞單獨給你準備了禮物
Gloria got you her own gift.
包裝得真精美
Wow, this is wrapped so nicely!
是我包的
I did that.
在當代是門失落的藝術
It's a lost art in this modern age
人們點擊幾下就在網上把禮物送出去了
where people simply click and ship gifts over the Internet.
寶貝 正常點
Papi, just be normal.
我們看看 這是
Let's see. It is, uh...
真絲枕頭嗎
some kind of silk pillow?
不止如此
Well, it's more than that.
你看 側面有一個開關
See, there's a switch on the side,
躺上去時能播放大海的聲音
and when you lay on it, it-it plays ocean sounds for you.
能幫助你放松
You know, I-it helps you relax.
至少不是轉送別人的禮物
At least it's not a re-gift.
-你怎么能忍受跟他過日子 -我
- How do you live with this? - I...
這樣吧
Tell you what.
不如我們再拆一個禮物
How about we do one more gift, and then
-然后吃蛋糕休息一下再拆 -好
we take a break for cake and do the rest after? Yeah.
給 鄧菲太太 這是我和海莉送的
Here, Mrs. Dunphy. This is from me and Haley.
謝謝你 迪蘭
Mm, thank you, Dylan.
但我不得不說
Although I have to say,
今年你們已經給我足夠的大禮了
you have given me enough gifts this year already.
我再次為搞大您女兒肚子的事道歉
Again, I'm very sorry about impregnating your daughter.
是啊
Yeah.
這是什么
What is this?
是臺香薰機
It's an aromatherapy machine.
你把精油加進去
See, you put in oils
應該能幫你緩解一天的壓力
that are supposed to help you with the stress of the day.
好吧 我們看看
Alright, well... let's see.
目前為止 我收到了全天水療
So far, I have gotten a spa day,
三份按摩
three massages,
冥想課 海洋枕頭
a meditation class, an ocean pillow,
發泄球棒 和一臺小機器
a rage bat, and a little machine
欺騙我的鼻子讓我平靜下來
that's supposed to trick my nose into calming me down.
為什么每個人都覺得我精神緊繃
Why does everyone think I'm so tense?
你的夜間牙套都咬爛了
You bit through your night guard.
你把我勒得太緊了
You're squeezing me too hard.
上周 你把藥劑師罵哭了
And last week, you made the pharmacist cry.
那是因為她不肯再賣我速達菲
That's because he wouldn't sell me any more Sudafed.
全家都病了
The entire family was sick.
我不是要制冰毒
I was not cooking meth.
你們知道嗎 我根本不想吃蛋糕
You know what? I don't even want cake.
我真的不喜歡你們這樣評判我
I really don't appreciate being criticized like this,
特別是在我生日這天
especially on my birthday.
那是我的禮物 晚點再拆
Um, that's my gift. Open later.
曼尼和我同一天過生日
Manny and I share a birthday,
所以我總是大張旗鼓博取注意
so I always do something big to get attention.
快看 不用手扶
Look! No hands!
-做得好 孩子 -太棒了 寶貝
- Way to go, kid! - Bravo, papi!
大伙 快看
Hey, guys! Check it out.
我騎獨輪車去上鋼琴課
Unicycling to my piano lesson.
我們真為你驕傲
Wow! We're so proud of you!
太厲害了
Now, that's impressive.
生日快樂 喬
Happy birthday, Joe!
原本挺快樂的
It was!
不用說大家也知道
It goes without saying
我是家族里最優秀的表演者
I'm the best performer in the family.
我今年過生日時 決定辦一場才藝演出
This year, for my birthday, I decided to have a talent show
好讓大家都開始稱贊這事實
so they all start saying it.
等等
Wait.
今天是才藝演出嗎 我都不知道
It's a talent show? I-I didn't know that.
邀請函上寫了啊
It said so on the invitation.
米奇爾
Mitchell?
我就隨便掃了一下
I only skimmed it.
這下糟了
This is a disaster.
我們可什么都沒有準備
We didn't prepare anything!
? 沒有什么能比卡羅萊納的早晨 ?
♪ Nothing could be finer than to be in Carolina ♪
Carolina in the Morning - Gus Kahn
? 更加美妙 ?
♪ In the morning ♪
? 沒人能比我的摯愛更加甜美 ?
♪ No one could be sweeter than my sweetie... ♪
真不敢相信他們車里有成對的馬甲
I can't believe they had matching vests in their car.
暴脾氣叔叔 你為什么這么生氣
Uncle Grumpy, why are you so angry?
因為總統想建隔離墻
Because the President wants to build a wall!
是啊 是挺悲哀的
Ay, yeah, that is very sad.
只是對我來說
Sad for me,
因為我又沒錢又丑
because I have no money and I am ugly.
你不一樣 他會讓你進來的 因為你有錢
For you, he would let you in because you have money
還是大胸美女
and you have the boobs.
我都不知道暴脾氣叔叔會講政治哏
I never thought Uncle Grumpy would go political.
我就知道我還不行
I knew I wasn't ready!
? 蝴蝶翩翩起舞 ?
♪ Butterflies all flutter up ♪
? 親吻美麗花朵 ?
♪ And kiss each little buttercup... ♪
斯黛拉 轉圈圈
Stella, walk in a circle.
斯黛拉 坐下
Stella, sit.
砰
Bang!
可惜差一點哦 爸
Ohh. Ah. Close, Dad.
沒有 我就是教她抱住槍口
No, I taught her to go for the gun.
自從我看了那部恐怖片
The banjo scares me ever since
班卓琴就給我留下了陰影
I saw that creepy film.
等等 那個電影叫什么來著
Wait. What was it called, again?
《激流四勇士》嗎
"Deliverance"?
不是 是《布偶大電影》
No. The Muppet Movie.
他是三趾樹蛙 她是兩趾樹蛙
He was a three-toed tree toad, but a two-toed toad was she.
三趾樹蛙
The three-toed tree toad
想得到兩趾樹蛙的心
tried to win the two-toed shetoad's heart,
因為三趾樹蛙喜歡
for the three-toed tree toad loved the ground
兩趾樹蛙腳下的土地
that the two-toed tree toad trod.
"樹蛙腳下的土地" 發送
"...tree toad trod." And sent.
太厲害了
Stop it!
西部最快拇指
Fastest thumbs in the West!
? 如果我能有一天擁有阿拉丁神燈 ?
♪ If I had Aladdin's lamp for only a day ♪
? 我會許個愿 這是我要許的愿望 ?
♪ I would make a wish, and here's what I'd say ♪
? 沒有什么能比卡羅萊納的早晨 ?
♪ Nothing could be finer than to be in Carolina ♪
? 更加美妙 ?
♪ In the mooorniiing ♪
大家都知道 雪莉和我是因為我們
As you all know, Sherry and I met
對即興表演共同的愛而相遇相愛
and fell for each other over our love of improv.
那么現在 我們是在一個浪漫的餐廳
So, we're at a romantic restaurant.
好的
Okay.
晚餐很好吃
That dinner was delicious.
我真不敢相信你選了這個地方
I can't believe you chose this place.
這里的主廚是我前男友
The chef is my ex-boyfriend.
瘋子前男友嗎
The crazy one?
是的
Yes.
他嫉妒心很強
He's very jealous,
我擔心他對你的食物動了手腳
and I'm scared he did something to your food.
我感覺有點不太好[搞笑]
I am feeling a little funny.
我倒希望這能稍微搞笑點
I wish this were a little funny.
這個房間在轉嗎 我
I-Is this room spinning? I --
沒有
No.
我怕是中毒了
I was afraid of that.
那我最好趁還來得及趕緊做了
Well, then I better do this before it's too late.
這一部分是真的
And this part is real.
雪莉·夏克爾
Sherry Shaker,
我以前都是獨角戲
I used to be a one-man show,
直到你從舞臺左側進場
and then you entered from stage left,
我墜入愛河
and I fell in love.
我希望
I want you
你能永遠做我的屏幕伴侶
to be my scene partner forever.
親愛的 讓我們一起讓朋友們見證
Darling, let's force our friends to sit through
我們的余生
the rest of our lives together.
你愿意嫁給我嗎
Will you marry me?
我的天
Oh, my God.
曼尼
Manny!
不要
No!
你為什么要這么做
Why would you do this?!
至少現在你的鋼琴表演不是最糟心的了
You gotta be feeling better about that piano.
我都不想聊我今年的生日
I'd rather not talk about my birthday this year.
? 祝你生日快樂 親愛的莉莉 ?
♪ Happy birthday, dear Lily ♪
? 祝你生日快樂 ?
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
我還是不敢相信雪莉拒絕了我
I still can't believe Sherry said no
還跟我分手
and broke up with me.
那他想怎么樣 他現在才二十歲
What does he expect? He's 20 years old.
在全家人面前搞了個想象的餐廳求婚
He proposed in front of his family at a pretend restaurant.
說好的"我愿意"情節呢
Whatever happened to "Yes and"?
杰 我什么都試過了
Jay, I've tried everything.
你快說點什么能讓他好受點的話吧
Please say something to him that will make him feel better.
行吧
Fine.
孩子 別想了
Kid, let it go.
都四天了
It was four days ago.
好了 來許個愿
Alright, let's make a wish!
我希望我死了
I wish I were dead.
好啦
Alright.
許完了 挺好
There we go.
海莉和我計劃了好多年
Haley and I have had this plan for years
等我21歲的時候 我們要一起去酒吧
that when I turn 21, we'd hit the bars together.
但是因為她懷孕了 我算是在喝兩人份
But since she's pregnant, I was drinking for two.
準確地說 四人份
Technically, four.
我告訴你 海莉·鄧菲
Let me tell you something, Haley Dunphy.
你知道我有多佩服你嗎
Do you know how much I admire you?
知道嗎
Do you?
五體投地
So much!
我忙上忙下累得像狗一樣
While I was working my butt off,
你卻能在外面逍遙自在
you were out there having fun!
無憂無慮
Not worrying about anything --
不想學校 不想工作
not school, not work...
不想避孕
not condoms.
看看你 挺著大肚子
Look at you -- all preg-a-nant.
或許我應該讓比爾也把我肚子搞大
Maybe I should have Bill come get me pregnant.
這樣我們就可以一起懷孕了 那多有意思
Then we can be pregnant together! That would be fun!
我的手機呢
Where's my phone?
我要給他發短信讓他過來搞大我肚子
I'm gonna text him to come get me pregnant.
你知道嗎
You know what?
都什么時代了
It's 2000-something.
是我要搞大他的肚子
I'm gonna get him pregnant!
我真想念喝傻的日子
I miss drinking.
不像其他人 我喜歡我的生日
Unlike some people, I love my birthday.
這是一年中可以以我為中心的一天
It's the one day a year that can be all about me.
好了 我覺得我們每個人輪流
So, um, I thought it would be fun
講講自己愛小卡哪一點
if we all went around the room
肯定很有意思
and say what we love about Cam.
這可真是意外 不過你要堅持的話就來吧
Well, that's out of nowhere, but if you insist.
海莉 不如你先開始
Haley, why don't you go first?
我嗎 好的
Oh, me? Okay.
這個嘛 我愛小卡舅舅
Well, um... I love Uncle Cam
因為他很有意思而且穿衣有品
because he is fun and dresses with flair.
真不好意思
Oh, my gosh.
還有 我也愛他讓米奇爾舅舅很幸福這點
And, uh, I love that he makes my Uncle Mitchell happy.
還有還有 我愛你們 因為你們最先知道
Oh, also, I love that you guys were the first ones
我懷孕了卻沒有給我講大道理評判我
to find out I was pregnant and you never judged me.
等一等 你這話什么意思
Wait a minute. What are you talking about?
我以為我們是同時知道的
I thought we all found out at the same time.
這個嘛
Oh, uh... Well...
米奇爾 你早知道她懷孕了卻沒有告訴我
Mitchell, you knew she was pregnant and you didn't tell me?
我覺得這件事不該由我向你開口嘛
I didn't think it was my place.
好啦 下一個是誰
Anyway, who's next?
誰來說"我最愛小卡的是他..."
"What I love about Cam is..."
我只是希望你起碼能有一次在背后支持我
I just wish you would have my back just once.
看來她沒有用我送她的"按摩器"
I don't think she's been using my gift.
-? 祝小卡生日快樂 ? -停 別唱了
- ♪ Happy birthday to Cam, happy... ♪ - Stop. Drop it.
歡迎來到我的世界
Welcome to my world.
我生日的時候 大家只在乎愛哭鬼曼尼
At my birthday, all anyone cared about was weepy Manny
被他女朋友給甩了
'cause Sherry broke up with him.
她現在有新男朋友了
She has a boyfriend now.
干得漂亮 莉莉
Way to go, Lily.
干得漂亮
Way to go!
您老貴庚啊
How old are you?
快51了 再...
I turn 51 in, uh...
這么多天就是了
this many days.
我老爸也有過中年危機
My dad had a midlife crisis, too.
我在他的公寓里有只倉鼠
I have a hamster at his condo.
不 不是中年危機
No. N-No midlife crisis.
我只是覺得... 人活到老學到老嘛
I just think you're -- you're never too old to learn.
求你高抬貴手 別靠近我媽
Just stay away from my mom.
我媽對廢柴沒有抵抗力
She has a thing for losers.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
我們是不是該帶你去醫院了
Should we take you to the hospital?
對啊 陣痛的間隔越來越短了
Yeah, the contractions are getting closer together.
不行 老爸是下一個
No. Dad is next.
我可以再為他多忍幾分鐘
I can hold it for a few minutes, okay?
我不想搞砸他的發表會
I don't want to screw this up for him.
要命 在那之后出場也太慘了
Yikes. Hate to follow that.
兄臺你準備用那首曲子技驚四座
What are you gonna dazzle us with?
《致愛麗絲》
"Fur Elise."
哪個調 荒腔走調的調嗎
In which key -- "B" obvious?
下一位 是我唯一會剃胡子的學生
Next up, the only student of mine who shaves.
菲爾·鄧菲
Phillip Dunphy.
當我滿50歲的時候 我發誓要做一些
When I turned 50, I vowed to do some things
走出自己舒適圈的事情
to take me out of my comfort zone
讓自己不會松懈倦勤 在此我想感謝我的家人
and keep me on my toes, and I want to thank my family
永遠當我最大的拉拉隊
for being my biggest cheerleaders.
我也愛你 閨女
I love you, too, honey.
不是 海莉要生了
No, Haley's going into labor!
我們得送她去醫院了 老公
We've got to get her to the hospital, honey!
我試著忍住了 對不起 老爸
Oh! I tried to hold it! I'm sorry, Dad!
天啊 抱歉了 各位
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry, everyone!
真"巧"啊
Convenient.
好 太棒啦 走
Yes! Great! Come on!
親愛的 你真棒
Great work, honey.
替我跟你老母問聲好
Tell your mom I say hi.
迪蘭
Dylan!
一切都還好吧
Is everything okay?
不
No.
是一切都太美妙了
Everything's amazing.
你干嘛這么嚇人啊
Why would you say it that way?
海莉沒事
Haley's fine.
她好勇敢
She was so brave.
孩子們也很棒
And the babies are great!
我都等不及要見他們了
I can't wait to see them!
等他們接受完檢查就行了
As soon as they're done getting checked out.
我現在去把孩子抱來
I'm gonna go get them now.
等等
Wait, wait.
性[別]呢
What about the sex?
醫生說我跟海莉得起碼休息六周
Doctor says not for six weeks.
請問這里是鄧菲房嗎
Is this the Dunphy suite?
孩子的媽怎么樣啦
Oh, how's the mommy?
消毒液 各位 都來用
Hand sanitizer, everyone. Here you go.
你還好嗎 孩子
How you doing, kiddo?
有點累 我昨晚太操勞了
A little tired. I overdid it last night.
兒子 我覺得他不是在問你
I don't think he was talking to you, buddy.
有點心力交瘁
It's overwhelming.
心里有點五味雜陳
Just feeling so many different emotions.
我還挺棒的
I'm also doing great.
我生了一個兒子一個女兒
I have a son and a daughter,
等他們把孩子弄干凈就行了 他們超可愛
and once they washed them off, they were really cute.
打算起什么名字呢
Oh, what are their names?
我們打算先不決定 等麻醉過了再說
We're gonna put a pin in that until the drugs wear off.
沒人的孫子們應該被起做皮克斯與科切拉
Nobody needs grandchildren named Pixar and Coachella.
菲爾 這是給你的
Phil, this is for you.
是... 提前給你的生日禮物
It's a...little early birthday present.
而我承認 這禮物是轉送的二手貨
And I admit, this one is a re-gift.
"世上最棒的外公"
"World's Best Grandfather."
這是海莉出生時我送給你的杯子
It's the mug I gave you when Haley was born.
你這些年來居然一直留著
You kept it all these years.
是啊 但是... 現在是你的了
Yeah. But, uh... it's yours now.
我用不上了 我有個新頭銜
I don't need it anymore. I got a new title.
"外曾祖母"嗎
"Great grandma"?
靠 我買錯個了
Oh, hell. I grabbed the wrong one.
給你
Here.
我就數到三
I'm going to count to three.
好的
Yeah.
發布會怎么樣了 菲爾
Hey, how was your recital, Phil?
我把場面搞得一團亂
Oh, I messed it all up for him.
抱歉了 老爸
Sorry about that, Dad.
我知道那是你今年的大目標
I-I know that was your big goal for the year.
我現在有個更大的目標了
I have a better one now.
米阿莫費黑摸索[西語]
Mi ano fue hermoso.
我今年很美
My year was beautiful.
"阿諾"才是"年"
"Año" means "year."
"阿莫"是"屁眼"
"Ano" means "Anus."
還是通啦
Still works.
各位
Hey, everybody.
孩子們呢 我想見見他們
Ay, where are the babies? I want to see them.
這件事很難跟你們開口
There's no easy way to say this.
但米奇爾跟小卡說想表演一段
Mitch and Cam have a whole thing they want to do.
天啊 比我想的還慘
Oh, God. It's worse than I thought.
? 爸爸 有頭獅子出生了 ?
♪ Nants ingonyama bagithi baba ♪
天啊 我愛死了
Oh, my God! I love it so much!
? 是生命的循環 ?
♪ It's the circle of life ♪
真不敢相信他們車里有成對的袍子
I can't believe they had matching robes in their car.
? 帶領著我們向前 ?
♪ And it moves us all ♪
他們真是太美了
They're so beautiful!
? 穿越絕望與希望 ?
♪ Through despair and hope ♪
你做得很棒
Good job.
你們兩個都會有狗狗床
You're both gonna get dog beds.
? 越過信念與愛 ?
♪ Through faith and love ♪
下一個輪到你啦
You're next, huh?
行行行 我就隨口一說
Okay. Okay. I'm just saying.
? 是那循環 ?
♪ It's the circle ♪
真棒 孩子
Good job, kid.
? 那生命的循環 ?
♪ The circle of life ♪
天啊 他還在哭嗎
Oh... Is he still crying?
對啊 都哭了幾小時了
Yeah. Has been for hours...
我本來以為他哭睡了呢
I thought he cried himself to sleep.
可憐的小家伙
Poor little guy.
他吃過東西了嗎
Has he eaten anything?
我一個小時前喂過他了
I fed him an hour ago.
真是厲害 他們一個好得不行
It's amazing how one can be fine
而另一個哭得這么凄慘
and the other one is so upset.
你去睡吧
You go up to bed.
我睡前最后再去看他一回
I'll check him up one last time.
謝了 老媽
Thanks mom.
這不是我勇敢的大男孩嗎
There is my big brave boy.
雪莉預定要去拍一個牙膏廣告了
Sherry booked a toothpaste commercial.
我接下來要整天看到她美麗的笑容了
I'm going to have to see that beautiful smile all the time.
來來來 哭吧哭吧
There, there, let it out.